Finding Aid for the Russell Birdwell Papers LSC.0114
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 1. Client files
  - 1.1 Persons and Companies
    - Young, Loretta--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Young, Loretta--Press releases and biography, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Young, Loretta--Press releases and biography, ca. 1939-1941 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Yurka, Blanche, ca. 1945 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Yurka, Blanche--Clippings, 1943 March 25 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Yurka, Blanche--Clippings and brochures, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Yurka, Blanche--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Yurka, Blanche--Notes, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Yurka, Blanche--Press releases, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Zorina, Vera--Biography and interviews, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Zorina, Vera--Clippings and press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Zorina, Vera--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - 1.2 Movies, Radio Shows, and Events
    Contains items pertaining to specific movies, radio shows, and other events publicized by Birdwell.
    - Adam Had Four Sons--Press releases, ca. 1940 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      Based on the novel "Legacy".
    - Adventures of Tom Sawyer, The--Campaign book, ca. 1938 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - D-Day Demonstration--Correspondence and memoranda, 1944 May-June (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - D-Day Demonstration--Press releases, 1944 May-June (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - D-Day Demonstration--Programs, 1944 June (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Four Feathers--World preview programs, 1939 July 20 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Franco-British War Relief dinner dance, ca. 1939 December-1940 January (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Garden of Allah, The, ca. 1936 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Garden of Allah, The--Campaign book, ca. 1936 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Gone with the Wind--facts pamphlet and premiere announcement, ca. 1939 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - It Happened in Hollywood, ca. 1938 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Little Lord Fauntleroy, ca. 1936 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Made for Each Other--Trade and press showing program, 1939 January 31 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Major Barbara--Premiere programs, ca. 1941 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - March Field show, ca. 1941 September (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Mitza Babington radio show, ca. 1941 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - National Theatre contest--Judging committee, ca. 1945 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - National Theatre contest--Submissions, ca. 1945 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - National Theatre contest--Submissions, ca. 1945 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - National Theatre contest--Submissions, ca. 1945 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Nothing Sacred--Campaign book, ca. 1937 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Nothing Sacred--Lady Godiva stunt, ca. 1937 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Nurse Edith Cavell--Press releases and preview program, ca. 1939 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Program autographed by Anna Neagle and Herbert Wilcox.
    - Outlaw, The--Advertising, 1942 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Outlaw, The--Clippings, 1942 October-1943 March (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Outlaw, The--Correspondence, 1943 March 2 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Outlaw, The--Fan mail, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Outlaw, The--Miscellaneous, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Outlaw, The--Miscellaneous, 1940-1941 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Outlaw, The--Music, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Outlaw, The--Planting, 1941 July 17-22 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Outlaw, The--Planting, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Outlaw, The--Planting, ca. 1942 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Outlaw, The--Premiere, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Outlaw, The--Press releases, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Outlaw, The--Printing plates, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Outlaw, The--Stageshow, 1942 November-December (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Outlaw, The--Toland, Gregg--Press releases, ca. 1941 January (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Outlaw, The--Trailer, ca. 1942 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Park Avenue Canteen, ca. 1942 September (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Previews--Miscellaneous, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Prisoner of Zenda--Press releases, ca. 1937 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Rebecca--Trade and press showing programs, ca. 1940 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Scramby Amby (radio show), ca. 1944 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - So Ends Our Night--Trade and press showing invitations, 1941 January 21 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Star Is Born, A--Campaign book, ca. 1937 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Star Is Born, A--Press Releases, ca. 1936-1937 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Star Is Born, A--Press Releases, ca. 1936-1937 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Thief of Bagdad, The--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1940 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Thief of Bagdad, The--Premiere and preview programs and invitations, 1940 October (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Premiere program autographed by Alexander Korda
    - Thief of Bagdad, The--Press releases, ca. 1940 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Thief of Bagdad, The--Press releases, ca. 1940 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Thief of Bagdad, The--Press releases and notes, ca. 1940 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Too Many Husbands--Press releases, ca. 1940 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - When the Lights Go On Again, ca. 1944 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Young in Heart--Press Releases, ca. 1938 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Young in Heart--Press Releases, ca. 1938 (Box 50, Folder 3)
- 2. Correspondence
  Contains extensive correspondence between Birdwell and many other people. Birdwell's practice of occasionally filing newspapers clippings among correspondence has not been disturbed. Items are primarily arranged by first letter of the correspondent's surname, although occasionally items are filed by subject as noted on the item.
  - No Subseries assigned
    - A surnames, ca. 1941 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - A surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Altstock, L. F., ca. 1940 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Armstrong, Lancelot, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - B surnames, ca. 1939-1947 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - B surnames, ca. 1939-1947 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - B surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - C surnames, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - C surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Crocker, Harry, ca. 1940 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - D surnames, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - D surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Davis, Bette, 1940 February 20 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Contains Davis autograph.
    - deMille, Cecil B., 1937 April (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Contains deMille autograph.
    - E surnames, 1941-1943 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - E surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - English correspondence, ca. 1941 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - F surnames, ca. 1940-1944 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - F surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Family, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Family, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - G surnames, ca. 1938-1944 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - G surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Gish, Lillian, 1941 July 25 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Contains Gish autograph.
    - H surnames, ca. 1939-1941 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - H surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Hammer Galleries, 1941 December 1 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Hannagan, Steve, ca. 1936-1937 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Hart, William S., 1944 March-April (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Contains Hart autographs.
    - Hoffman, Irving, ca. 1940 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Hughes, Carol, 1944 January-February (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Hynd, Alan, 1943-1944 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Hynd, Alan, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - I surnames, ca. 1942-1944 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - I surnames, ca. 1941-1944 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - J surnames, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - J surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Johnston, Alva, ca. 1944 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - K surnames, ca. 1940-1946 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - K surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - L surnames, ca. 1940-1944 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - L surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - M surnames, ca. 1938-1946 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - M surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - N surnames, 1940 December-1943 November (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - N surnames, ca. 1940-1942 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - O surnames, 1941 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - O surnames, ca. 1940-1942 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - O'Hara, Maureen, 1941 March 31 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      Contains O'Hara autograph.
    - P surnames, 1938-1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - P surnames, ca. 1939-1941 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Parsons, Louella, ca. 1940-1944 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      See also P surnames.
    - Pickford, Mary, 1940 October 16, 1944 September-October (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Pope, Frank, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Q-R surnames, ca. 1940-1944 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - R surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - S surnames, ca. 1936-1944 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - S surnames, ca. 1938-1942 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - S surnames, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Starr, Jimmy, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      See also Correspondence, S surnames
    - T surnames, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - T surnames, ca. 1939-1941 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - U surnames, 1941 September-1942 March (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - U surnames, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified correspondents, ca. 1936-1844 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - V surnames, 1941 July-1942 August (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - V surnames, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Vanderbilt, Cornelius Jr., ca. 1941-1943 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      See also office memoranda files.
    - W surnames, 1938 August-1944 December (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - W surnames, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Y surnames, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- 3. Personal
  Contains items about Birdwell and his writings, including publicity releases, newspaper and magazine clippings, and newspaper and magazine articles, as well as items about Birdwell's wife, Mabel Condon, and other family members.
  - No Subseries assigned
    - Biographical Encyclopedia of the World, 1944 March 20-29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Biographical material, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Biographical material, ca. 1938-1945 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Biographical material, ca. 1939-1947 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Bird's Eye Views--Ideas, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Birds-Eye Views column, 1944 April-June (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Birds-Eye Views column--Correspondence, 1944 May-June (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bird's-Eye Views columns, ca. 1944 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Bird's-Eye Views columns, ca. 1944 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Birds-Eye Views columns, 1944 May (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Birdwell family history--Correspondence, 1946 November-1947 January (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Birdwell, Mabel (Condon), ca. 1936-1942 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Birdwell, Tomasita, 1943 September, 1945 October 25 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Birdwell, Tomasita, ca. 1936 (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Books--Clippings, ca. 1939-1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Clippings about Russell Birdwell, ca. 1936-1946 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Clippings about Russell Birdwell, ca. 1936-1946 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Contracts (unsigned), 1947 January-February (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Coronet article about Russell Birdwell, ca. 1944 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Great Anthony, The (play)--Correspondence and notes, ca. 1942 September-1943 March (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - House, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Housing ideas--Clipping, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - I Ring Doorbells, ca. 1938-1946 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - I Ring Doorbells (movie)--Press releases, ca. 1945 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - I Ring Doorbells (sheet music), ca. 1938-1939 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - I Ring Doorbells--Clippings, 1938 September-1939 May (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - I Ring Doorbells--Copies sent, ca. 1943-44 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - I Ring Doorbells--Correspondence, 1944 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - I Ring Doorbells--Press book, ca. 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - I Ring Doorbells--Press releases and press book, ca. 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - I Ring Doorbells--Publicity, 1938 December-1939 January (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Ideas, ca. 1942-1945 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Lecture ideas, ca. 1938-1939 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Letters from England, 1941 October (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Letters from England, 1941 October (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Memorandum re residence, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Merchant of Death (film production project), ca. 1946 February (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - New Yorker series about Russell Birdwell, 1944 August 19-September 9 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings by and about Birdwell, 1936 March-1942 April (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings by and about Birdwell, 1936 May-1944 June (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings by and about Birdwell, ca. 1939 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings by and about Birdwell, ca. 1936 July-1943 July (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Party ideas, ca. 1936-1937 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Picture ideas, ca. 1945 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Play ideas, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Press releases, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Press releases, ca. 1942-1947 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Press releases about Birdwell, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Press releases, speeches, and correspondence, ca. 1936-1946 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Press releases, speeches, and correspondence, ca. 1936-1946 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Radio ideas, ca. 1936-1946 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Speeches--Correspondence and publicity, ca. 1938 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Stories, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Includes Bird's Eye Views columns
    - Tags for art and furniture purchases, ca. 1936-1946 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Valentine, Cherie and Tomasita (Birdwell), ca. 1941 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Women in Battle Dress--Articles for Journal-American, ca. 1942 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Women in Battle Dress--Clippings, 1942 December-January (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Women in Battle Dress--Clippings and press releases, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Women in Battle Dress--Manuscript, ca. 1942 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Women in Battle Dress--Publicity and Reviews, 1942 November-1943 February (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 4. Photographs
  Contains black-and-white and color negatives, black-and-white prints, and printing plates.
  - No Subseries assigned
    - Bickford, Charles, and Mrs. Lt. Colonel Russell E. Clarke, ca. 1944 May 9 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Birdwell, Russell, undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Birdwell, Russell, undated (Box 58, Folder 8)
      Printing plates.
    - Birdwell, Russell, with charm contest winners, 1938 December 16 (Box 58, Folder 18)
      Charm contest winners are Rosemary Murphy, Jean Hilliker, Jane Beebe, and Lady Katrine Fine.
    - Boyer, Charles, undated (Box 58, Folder 26)
    - Brown, Joe E., and other unidentified persons, ca. 1944 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Brown, Joe E.--at New Guinea hospitals, ca. 1941-1945 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Carol of Romania, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Carol, King of Romania, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Celotex, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Celotex, ca. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Celotex--Housing projects, ca. 1943 November (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Collins, Ted, Kate Smith, and others, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Coronet, undated (Box 58, Folder 27)
    - Crew--Naples to Algiers to Marrakech, undated (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Donaldson, Ted, and Dr. von Kleinsmid, undated (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Dorothy, Miss (Dorothy Garland), ca. 1945 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Eitel, undated (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Fairbanks, Mr. and Mrs. Douglas, and Russell Birdwell, undated (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Fiji, undated (Box 58, Folder 32)
    - Gable, Reah, undated (Box 58, Folder 30)
    - Gaynor, Janet, and other, ca. 1936 (Box 58, Folder 15)
      Persons in photograph: Marquis C. Grimaldi, F. E. Evans, David O. Selznick, Armando Fleury de Barros, Jean Joseph Viala, Mrs. F. E. Evans, and Fredric March.
    - Gibson, Helen, in "The Detective's Peril", 1916 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Harrigan, Nedda (?), undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Hudson, Rochelle, undated (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - I Ring Doorbells party, ca. 1938-1939 (Box 58, Folder 29)
    - Korda, Alexander, undated (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Kosleck, Martin--Artwork, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Leigh, Vivien, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Leigh, Vivien, and Russell Birdwell, ca. 1938-1939 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      Taken on "Gone with the Wind" set.
    - Little Lord Fauntleroy--Pigeon stunt, ca. 1936 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Lombard, Carole, 1936 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Lupescu, Elena, ca. 1943 (Box 58, Folder 24)
    - Margo, undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Massey, Raymond, and Russell Birdwell, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Melnitz, Curtis, and Secretary of the C.I.D.A.L.C. Pillat, ca. 1936 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Menzies, William Cameron, undated (Box 58, Folder 21)
    - Moray, Helga, ca. 1942 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Neagle, Anna, and "Nurse Edith Cavell" preview, ca. 1939 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Noviska, Toni, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Noviska, Toni, undated (Box 58, Folder 31)
    - Photostats used for Saturday Evening Post story, undated (Box 58, Folder 25)
    - Pommer, Erich, undated (Box 58, Folder 33)
    - Ray, Rene, 1939 July (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - Rhonie, Aline, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Rubinstein, Arthur, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Russell, Jane, undated (Box 58, Folder 28)
    - Russell, Jane, Toni Seven, and Martha Tilton, undated (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Scott, Martha, undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Selznick, David O., F. E. Evans, Marquis C. Grimaldi, Armando Fleury de Barros, and Jean Joseph Viala, ca. 1936 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Shaw, Artie, undated (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Shearer, Norma, George Raft, and Russell Birdwell, undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Shepard, Elaine, and Gregary Bautzer, undated (Box 58, Folder 22)
    - Sidney, Sylvia, undated (Box 58, Folder 20)
    - Smith, Kate, ca. 1942 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Stancliff, Mildred Ray, ca. 1936 (Box 58, Folder 19)
    - Stevens, K. T., ca. 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Stone, Michael, undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified child, undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified subjects, undated (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified subjects, undated (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Whelan, Arleen, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Woodworth, Marjorie, ca. 1942 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Young, Loretta, ca. 1939 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Young, Loretta, undated (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Young, Loretta (?), undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- 5. Office
  Contains items pertaining to the administration of Birdwell's office, including extensive memoranda among staff members.
  - 5.1 Memoranda
    Contains internal memoranda between Birdwell and his staff members. Many items contain notes about Birdwell's clients.
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1941 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1940 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1941 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1941 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1940-1942 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Armstrong, Dale, ca. 1940-1942 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1941-1944 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1940 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1940 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1940 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1940 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1941-1943 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1944 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1941 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1941 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Beck, Myer P., ca. 1941-1944 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Blake, Helen, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Blake, Helen, 1943 August-November (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Boesen, Vic, 1941 September-December (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Borsten, Orin, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Browne, Lillian, 1942 March-April (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Bulloch, Charles, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Bulloch, Charles, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Butterworth, Ethel, ca. 1940 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Carroll, Alene, 1944 December (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Coke, Kathryn, ca. 1941 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Coke, Kathryn, ca. 1941 August (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Condon, Charles R., ca. 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Condon, Charles R., 1942-1943 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Condon, Charles R., ca. 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Condon, Charles R., 1943 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Condon, Mabel, ca. 1944 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      See also Birdwell family correspondence
    - Coughlin, Gene, 1941 March-April (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Daggett, Charles, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Daggett, Charles, ca. 1942 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Dimond, Don, ca. 1944 October-December (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Doherty, Tom, ca. 1940 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Ettinger, Ed, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Ettinger, Ed, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Flynn, Joan, ca. 1940 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Friedrichsen, Frank, ca. 1941 January-March (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Frye, Stuart, 1941 March-April (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Gilbert, Jane, ca. 1944 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Glass, George, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Glass, George, ca. 1940 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Glass, George, ca. 1940 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Glass, George, ca. 1940 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Glass, George, ca. 1939 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Henry, Jim, ca. 1941 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Henry, Jim, 1941 July-September (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Hipple, William, ca. 1940 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Hogan, James, ca. 1940 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Howe, Melba, ca. 1941-1944 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Howe, Melba, ca. 1941 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Howe, Melba, ca. 1939-1942 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Howe, Melba, ca. 1941-1944 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Howe, Melba, ca. 1936-1938 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Jager, Elise, 1944 August-1945 January (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Lane, Helene, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Lane, Helene, ca. 1941-1944 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Lane, Helene, ca. 1941-1944 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Lynch, W. Ware, 1944 December (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Maren, Lew, ca. 1940 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Meyer, Lorraine, 1943 December 13 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1940-1945 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, ca. 1941 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Moeller, Betty, 1940 October 15 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Morrison, Denis, ca. 1940 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - O'Neill, Honey, 1942 May-June (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - O'Neill, Honey, 1942 October 14 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Parks, Jackson, ca. 1940 May-June (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Pessis, Erman, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Pfund, Louise, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Pfund, Louise, 1941 July-1942 November (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Pfund, Louise, 1941, 1943 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Planting reports, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Schenk, Floyd, 1940, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Schenk, Floyd H., ca. 1941-1943 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Sherman, Joe, 1940 September 27 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Sillery, Bruce, ca. 1940 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Simmons, Jim, 1941 June-July (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Staff, 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Staff, ca. 1940 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Vanderbilt, Cornelius Jr., ca. 1943 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Vanderbilt, Cornelius Jr., ca. 1943 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - 5.2 Other